Alison A. Schreckengast Full-Stack Developer

alischreck@gmail.com, https://github.com/Alischrec, (985) 232-8839, Seattle, WA, https://alischrec.github.io/Portfolio/, https://www.linkedin.com/in/alison-schreckengast/

SUMMARY:

Full stack web developer with an extensive background in psychology, literature, and client-side interactions. Currently working as a Technical Support Specialist utilizing my capabilities as a problem-solver for client-facing issues as well as working closely with the development team. Passionate about web development and continuous learning, recently completed a 24 week-long course and logged over 100 classroom hours of coding at University of Washington's coding bootcamp.

SKILLS:

Proficient: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, Node js, React, Git, SQL, MySQL, GitHub, Object Oriented Programming, DDL & DML, Material-UI, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Mongoose

Knowledgeable: Foundation, Azure DevOps

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:

Dumbbells & Donuts

https://github.com/Alischrec/Dumbbells_and_Donuts | https://alischrec.github.io/Dumbbells_and_Donuts/ This is a web application that allows you to enter workout and nutritional information used to track the user's health and wellness progress by the BMI calculation.

- Collaborated with a team of 4 in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, git, and debugging.
- Completed this web application in less than 2 weeks, collaborating remotely using Zoom and
- Front End Developer built HTML and CSS components and assisted with API routing and local
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Responsive Design, Foundation, ¡Query, local storage, Github Pages

Naughty or Nice

https://github.com/NirmalaAbothu/Naughty_or_Nice_I https://evening-springs-93825.herokuapp.com/

This is a web application that allows the user to track ongoing holiday gift lists throughout the year.

- Collaborated with a team of 4 to design, develop, debug, and deploy the web application.
- Thorough Documentation of all code changes through appropriate change control.
- Front End Developer built Handlebar components, CSS, and design while assisting on back end development.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Responsive Design, Materialize, ¡Query, Node.js, MySQL2, MySQL Workbench, Seguelize, Express.is, Passport, Handlebars, Nodemon, Heroku

Workout Tracker

https://github.com/Alischrec/Mongoose_WorkoutTracker | https://safe-fjord-74005.herokuapp.com/

This is a web application that allows the user to track daily workouts while saving the user's progress to a database displayed through an easy to use UX.

- Completed the web application within 1 week, working through various bugs and troubleshooting issues.
- Identified, analyzed, and interpreted trends and patterns in complex data sets
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Responsive Design, Node.js, Express.js, Nodemon, MongoDB, Mongoose, Heroku

EMPLOYMENT:

*What made you good at your job/use numbers/metrics where you can.. Result oriented

Headset Inc., Seattle, WA

August 2017 - Present

Technical Support Specialist

August 2018- Present

Actively provide technical support via online active chat and support tickets to various clients while troubleshooting basic technological issues. Work closely as a liaison between clients and the development team.

- Maintained an overall satisfaction rating of 4.9 out of 5 for the year 2020, and 100% for the year of 2021.
- Maintained an Average Response Time (ART) of 0.17 seconds for the year of 2020, and 0.14 seconds for the year of 2021
- Worked through various technologies including Zendesk, Intercom, and Happy Fox.

Sales Development Representative

August 2017 - August 2018

Followed sales process to maintain an active pipeline of qualified leads for Account Executives as a trusted source.

- Researched accounts, identified prospects, and generated outbound opportunities to develop accounts.
- Navigated a high volume of sales inquiries and proactively reached out to prospects via email and phone calls
- Worked with various technologies including Intercom, SalesForce, Outreach, and MailChimp

Ruffalo Noel Levitz, Baton Rouge, LA

May 2017 - March 2018

Student Caller

Followed fundraising process to maintain an active pipeline of quality clientele.

- Received Top Fundraiser after \$1,000+ donations in 1 month.
- Navigated a high volume of potential donors while proactively reaching out to donors via direct phone calls.

EDUCATION:

University of Washington State Aug. 2020 - Feb. 2021 Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate

University of Louisiana Aug. 2012 - May 2017 B.S. in Science of Psychology & B.A. in English Literature, minor in Sociology